cratejoy.com 2018-10-20

# Privacy Policy | Cratejoy

**Privacy Policy**

We love our community at Cratejoy. You’ve trusted us with a big responsibility, and we’re committed to upholding a high standard when it comes to our privacy practices. It’s important to us that you’re comfortable on Cratejoy, so we provide options for you to control how much information you share and your communication preferences. We use secure technologies and follow best practices. We believe in being transparent about our practices, which is why we provide a detailed Privacy Policy to explain how we gather, use and protect your information. We’ve pulled out the highlights here, in an effort to better communicate the key points.

By visiting Cratejoy’s website or using Cratejoy’s mobile applications, you are accepting the terms of this Privacy Policy. Any external links to other websites are clearly identifiable as such, and we are not responsible for the content or the privacy policies of these other websites.

Current policy published: May 22, 2018

**Your Privacy Rights**

**Introduction**

Cratejoy, Inc. (“Cratejoy” or “we” or “us”) has created this Privacy Policy in order to disclose its use of consumer data collected about you. This Privacy Policy is effective as of __________, 2018. Any questions regarding this policy should be directed by email to support@cratejoy.com. You may also contact Cratejoy at 720 Brazos Street #120, Austin, TX 78701.  The following discloses Cratejoy’s information gathering and dissemination practices for its social networking applications and website.

Cratejoy may be the Controller or Processor of your personal data provided to us by you or collected by us from you during your use of the website and/or applications, as outlined below. If you use the Cratejoy service, you consent to this policy and the use/sharing of your personal data as described herein.  You have the choice to opt-out of sharing your data, as described below, and control how we use and share your data. 

**Information Collected and Received**

Cratejoy may collect or receive information about each person who registers or enters information in any form with the Cratejoy website and/or applications including, but not limited to, user name, password, first and last name, email address, street address, gender, occupation, and interests Information can also be provided by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail, live-chat or otherwise. You can choose what information you want to share with Cratejoy, however if you choose to withhold any personal data requested by us, it may not be possible for you to gain access to certain parts of the Cratejoy website and/or application. Cratejoy does not require You to include sensitive information (e.g. racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union memberships, genetic data, biometric data, data concerning health or data concerning sexual orientation). In the event that you provide such sensitive information as listed above you acknowledge that you have provided Cratejoy explicit consent to receive such information. Cratejoy also collects information on the pages you access and other information you may volunteer, such as survey information.  Cratejoy may also collect user location information, as further described in the “Global Positioning System” paragraph below.

**Lawful Basis for Processing**

We will only collect and process your personal data where we have lawful basis. Our lawful basis include consent (where you have given it), where processing is necessary for the performance of a contract with you, and for the purposes of our legitimate interests or the legitimate interests of our third parties, provided that such interest does not outweigh your rights and freedoms. Examples of legitimate interest include but are not limited to: (i) complying with applicable law, (ii) protecting against security or other threats, (iii) administration of our business interests, including improvements and enhancements of our business, and (iv) customer relationship issues.  

**Your Rights: Access, Correction, Deletion**

We retain the personal data that you provide to us when you registered with the Cratejoy website and/or application or any other information that you volunteered while using the website and/or application for (i) as long as your account is active or (ii) otherwise for a limited period of time as long as we need to fulfill the purposes for which we have initially collected it, unless otherwise required by law. We retain any information provided as described in the Uses of Information below. 

You have the right to request access to the information that Cratejoy has on you. You can do this by contacting us at support@cratejoy.com. In order to comply with your request, we may have to verify your identity. If you believe that the information that we have about you is incorrect, you are able to contact us at support@cratejoy.com with the change request. Any data that is no longer needed for the purposes specific below will be deleted. You have the right to request the deletion of any personal data that we have on you. If you wish to do so, please contact us at support@cratejoy.com. Note that Cratejoy may not be able to delete any depersonalized data on you. 

**How We Use Your Information**

Cratejoy uses the information that we collect in order to operate and maintain our website and/or applications, and/or any other services provided to you. Cratejoy also uses your information in order to (i) send you marketing communications, (ii) respond to your questions and concerns and (iii) help our partners to improve their online offerings. 

We occasionally use other companies to perform services necessary to our operations. In the course of providing these services, those companies may have access to your personal information. By contractual agreement, those companies must treat your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. However, we will not be liable for any damages that may result from the misuse of your personal information by these companies.

Cratejoy may use your IP address to help diagnose problems with Cratejoy’s server and to administer Cratejoy’s web site. Your IP address may also be used to help identify you and your online profile and to gather broad demographic information.

**How We Share Your Information**

**(a) Personally, Identifiable Information**. Cratejoy will never sell your email address or any other personally identifiable information, to any third party without your permission. We may store personally identifiable information in locations outside the direct control of Cratejoy (for example, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers). Any personally identifiable information you elect to make publicly available on our websites and/or applications (such as posting comments, reviewing items, etc.) will be available to others. Except as described in this Section, we will not disclose your personally identifiable information to any third party except consultants working on our behalf, without notifying you of our intent to share the information and giving you an opportunity to prevent your information from being shared. From time to time, we may partner with companies based on the interests of our users. These partner companies will never see your email address or any other information that could identify you or be used to contact you directly.

**(b) Non-Personally Identifiable Information**. The Cratejoy site registration form may require users to give Cratejoy contact information (such as your name and email address) and demographic information (such as your zip code, age, or income level). Cratejoy uses your contact information from the registration form to send you information about Cratejoy and promotional material from some of Cratejoy’s partners. Your contact information may also be used to contact you when necessary. Cratejoy may use demographic and/or profile data to tailor your experience on the Cratejoy website and/or applications, show you content that Cratejoy thinks you may be interested in, and display content according to your preferences. The demographic and profile data will be shared with third parties ONLY on an aggregate basis.  Furthermore, Cratejoy shall have the right to retain records of all data pertaining to use of the website and applications including, but not limited to, usage, activity logs, and click-throughs. Cratejoy may disclose such data to third parties provided it is grouped with other Cratejoy users’ data and is presented in an aggregate form. 

**(c) We May Be Required to Share Your Information.** Cratejoy reserves the right to disclose information when required by law, such as by a subpoena or other legal proceedings. Cratejoy may also disclose your information if we reasonably believe it necessary to (i) comply with requests of law enforcement or other applicable law; (ii) to enforce any agreement between you and us; (iii) to protect the security and integrity of our site, applications, or services; and/or (iv) to protect us, our users or others. 

**(d) What Happens in the Event of a Change of Control:** We may be involved with an acquisition or divestiture of our business, products or services. Information we maintain including names and email addresses, and other information related to the Cratejoy service may be sold or transferred in connection with such transaction. We may also sell, assign or otherwise transfer such information in connection with a sale of all or substantially all of our business or assets. You will be notified via email and/or a notice on our site of any applicable change in ownership or uses of your information.

**(e) Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting**. We allow advertisers to display advertising on our sites and applications. Our advertisers may use technology such as cookies to gather information about your activities on multiple sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your activities and interests. The only way to opt out of the collection of any information through cookies or other tracking technology is through the settings in your browser or mobile device. Please review your browser or mobile device information for instructions on how to delete and disable cookies, and other tracking/recording tools (to learn more about cookies, clear gifs/web beacons and related technologies, you may wish to visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) and/or the Network Advertising Initiative’s online resources, at [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)). If you access the Cratejoy service, websites and/or applications on your mobile device, you may not be able to control tracking technologies through the settings. For more information, see the Cookies Section below. 

**(f) Testimonials**. We may also disclose, on an anonymous basis, statements made by our users. However, with your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If at any point you wish to update or delete your testimonial, please contact us at support@cratejoy.com. 

**How We Store and Process Your Information**

The information collected by Cratejoy may be processed and/or stored in the United States, European Union Member Nations, Canada, or any other country in which Cratejoy or its affiliates or service providers maintain operations. Cratejoy may transfer information that we collect, including personally identifiable information, to affiliated entities, or to other third parties across borders and from your country or jurisdiction of domicile to other countries or jurisdictions. If you are located in the European Union or other regions with laws restricting transferring of data, please note that we will comply with laws applicable to us.

**How We Protect Your Information**

Cratejoy is concerned with protecting your privacy and data, and therefore we use industry-standard technologies when transferring and receiving consumer data exchanged between Cratejoy and other companies to help ensure its security. This site has security measures in place designed to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under Cratejoy’s control. Cratejoy’s servers are backed up regularly and protected by security systems. However, we cannot ensure or guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us or guarantee that your information on the Cratejoy service may not be accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed by breach of any of our industry standard physical, technical or managerial safeguards. If you have any questions about security on our website and/or application, you can contact us at [info@cratejoy.com.](about:blank) We may use an outside help platform, and a credit card processing company to bill you if you purchase services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes.

**Children’s Privacy**

We do not knowingly collect any information from anyone who we know to be under the age of 13. If you are under the age of 18, you should use this website only with the involvement of a parent or guardian and should not submit any personal information to us. If we discover that a person under the age of 13 has provided us with any personal information, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to delete such person’s personal information from all Cratejoy systems.

**Do Not Track Requests  **

Your web browser may have a setting that allows you to automatically send a “Do Not Track” message to the websites you visit.  Cratejoy does not currently have technology to respond to such requests.

**Links**  
Cratejoy may create links to other web sites. Cratejoy will make a reasonable effort to link only to sites that meet similar standards for maintaining each individual’s right to privacy. However, many other sites that are not associated or authorized by Cratejoy may have links leading to our site. Cratejoy cannot control these links and Cratejoy is not responsible for any content appearing on these sites.

**International Privacy Laws**

If you are using the website and/or application from outside of the United States, be aware that you are sending your information (including any provided personal information) to the United States where our servers are located. Your information, therefore, may be transferred into, or back out of, the United States, depending on the type of information and how it is stored by Cratejoy. Note that these countries may have different data protection laws than your country of residence, however, our collection, storage and use of your personal data will at all times be governed by this Privacy Policy. 

**Amendments**

Cratejoy may amend this policy at any time. If Cratejoy is going to use personally identifiable information collected through the Cratejoy site in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, Cratejoy will notify users via email and/or by posting a notice on the Cratejoy site for thirty (30) days prior to such use. This Privacy Policy may not be otherwise amended except in a writing that specifically refers to this Privacy Policy and is physically signed by both parties.

**Successors and Assigns**

This Privacy Policy inures to the benefit of successors and assigns of Cratejoy.  

**Contacts**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, your dealings with this web site, or request access, changes or deletion to information we have about you, you can contact support@cratejoy.com. Upon request, Cratejoy will provide you with access to information (e.g., name, address, phone number) that Cratejoy collects and maintains about you. This site gives you the following options for changing, modifying or removing information previously provided: (i) email: support@cratejoy.com; or (ii) visit cratejoy.com.

**Opt-Out**

The Cratejoy site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from Cratejoy, except transactional correspondence. To opt-out of receiving our communications, you can (i) send email to support@cratejoy.com; or (ii) send postal mail to: Cratejoy, Inc., 720 Brazos Street #120, Austin, TX 78701.
